PETER BENVENUTO

Mississauga, ON L5A 1S1 416-456-3019 peterbenvenuto90@amail.com

Full Stack Web Developer

<u>peterbenvenuto.com</u> <u>github.com/PeterBen90</u> linkedin.com/in/peter-benvenuto/

Passionate about building beautiful and responsive front ends.

Specialize in Full Stack JavaScript development, and writing clean, accessible and testable code.

KEY SKILLS

Frontend/Markup: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, React, Redux, Material UI, ES6, RESTful APIs, AJAX, and Bootstrap Backend: NodeJS, ExpressJS Java, Groovy, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, SQL, Mongoose, JSON Web Tokens, and MongoDB Atlas Tools: Git, GitHub, GitLab, BitBucket, Sourcetree, Heroku, Netlify, MLab, Postman, Azure DevOps, Responsive Web Design, and Agile Development Testing: Mocha, Chai, Enzyme, Jest, Travis CI, and Junit

RECENT PERSONAL PROJECTS

<u>Travel Assistant +Plus</u> - Simple JQuery travel app which helps you plan your daily activities while you are visiting somewhere new. This app uses the OpenWeatherMap API, the Foursquare API and Google Places API. (<u>code</u>)

Quik Eatz - NodeJS and Jquery recipe storage platform that allows each user to create and post food and/or cocktail recipes. (code)

<u>Xperience</u> - React and NodeJS app that tracks experiences, allowing users to capture moments and post/save them. (<u>code</u>)

Playline Contest - A NodeJS and JQuery contest page that collects and stores valid emails in a remote MongoDB database. (code)

WORK HISTORY

InvestCloud Inc., Burlington, Ontario

Frontend Engineer/Integration Engineer, Sep 2018 - Present

Development of financial products. Mostly maintaining and updating apps using HTML, CSS and JS (Frontend). Assess and resolve data quality issues across multiple client accounts. Develop efficient ETL scripts using Java/Groovy to extract, compute and map client focused financial data Design RESTful web APIs to seamlessly extract client data from existing CRM systems. Maintain focus on application development, database modeling and overall integration development (Integration).

PLAYLINE, Toronto, Ontario (contract)

Lead Frontend Engineer, Jul 2018 - Sep 2018

Responsible for reporting directly to the CTO - Mostly maintaining and updating app using React and Redux on the frontend. Some experience working with their backend using PHP/Symfony and MYSQL. Experience working in an Agile Development environment and working on multiple assignments at once.

CHRYSLER CANADA, Brampton, Ontario

Logistics and Material Handling, Sep 2010 - Nov 2014 & Sep 2016 - Jun 2018

Organized 10 – 15 large trucks, tracking parts with software and station checklists. Also responsible for cross-training over 30 new employees in 25 different roles.

EDUCATION

THINKFUL - Brooklyn, NY

Thinkful Full Stack Web Development Program, Nov 2017 - May 2018

Six-month, intensive, mentor-led, course on modern full stack JavaScript development.

HUMBER COLLEGE - Toronto, ON

Business and Marketing Management, Sep 2016 - April 2017

A Post-graduate diploma in business and marketing management.

YORK UNIVERSITY - Toronto, ON **Political Science**, Sep 2011 - June 2014

An undergraduate degree in Political Science.